我真是全身散发着粗旷美啊  是不
I really am ruggedly handsome, aren't I?
那艾什利呢
What about Ashley?
我是说  我该告诉他吗
I mean, shouldn't I tell him?
宝贝  感情的事
Darling, in matters of the heart,
最好不要想太多
it's best not to overthink things.
妈  那是你根据以往经验给出的建议吗
That's your advice, mother, with your track record?
听她的恋爱建议
What chasm of doom has she led you to
会让你万劫不复
by way of her tips on romance?
我们刚才恰好在讨论
As it happens, we were discussing
如何应对神秘仰慕者
secret admirer etiquette.
有人暗恋你吗
You have a secret admirer?
我总以为暗恋很傻
I always thought it was silly,
但现在我觉得蛮有意思的
but now I'm kind of intrigued.
总之无需告诉艾什利
And there is no need to tell Ashley.
这个暗恋者到底是怎样
How exactly does a secret
向你表达爱慕的啊
admirer express his admiration?
他留了张纸条在我的存物柜
He left a note in my locker.
"当你走在走廊上
"As you walked down the hall,
斑驳的阳光掠过你亚麻色的马尾
a shard of sunlight glanced off your rope of flaxen hair
照得明亮晃眼  我便陶醉了"
and set it aglow, and I was enchanted."
噢  写得太诗意了
Oh, that's so poetic.
我想亚麻色的马尾是指法式麻花辫
I figure the rope of flaxen hair is my french braid,
我只在体育课后才这样扎
which I only wore after gym class,
所以说  他是在第四五节课之间
which means he saw me in the hall
在一楼的走廊上看见我的
on the first floor between fourth and fifth period.
等等  你这是在干嘛
Wait a minute. What are you doing?
缩小嫌疑人范围
Narrowing down suspects.
不  你怎能这样做
No, you can't do that.
那样会摧毁秘密的
No, you-- no, that'll ruin the secret.
这事就像是一部悬疑小说
No, it's like a mystery novel.
-你不能直奔结局  对吧  -不对
-You don't just go to the last page, do you? -Yes.
你真会这样
You do?
你不该这样  你不能...
Well, you shouldn't. It's not--you can't--
真相大白就没意思了
The--the joy doesn't come in knowing who did it.
等待的过程才有乐趣
The joy comes in the journey,
让结局
in allowing the ending
如动人的喜马拉雅山蓝罂粟般绽放
to blossom like some magnificent himalayan blue poppy,
-如...  -好了
- like a-- - Okay.
好吧  我不会揭开谜底的
Okay. I'll let him stay a secret.
听我的准没错  你会感谢我的
Mark my words. You'll thank me.
卡塞尔
Castle.
本案的受害人叫琳达·罗素
So our victim is Linda Russo.
她是一家电视公司的客户关系专员
She's a customer relations worker at a cable company.
也许有人对他们的服务不满
Maybe someone was unsatisfied with their service.
-我也是这么想的  -真的吗
- Yeah, that's what I was thinking. - You were?
清洁工在一堆盒子下面
Sanitation workers found her body
发现她的尸体
under a couple of boxes.
她住在两个街口外的24街和10街那边
She lives 2 blocks away, over at 24th and 10th.
看来她当时正在回家路上
Looks like she was on her way home.
早  蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
早
Hey.
怎么了
What?
呃...
Uh...
没事
It's nothing.
说  什么事
No, what?
只是她的...死相很平静
Well, she just... looks so peaceful.
把她弃尸这里的可不是什么平静的人
There's nothing peaceful about what put her here.
-她是被勒死的  -用绳子吗
- She was strangled. - With rope?
看来是的
So it appears.
卡塞尔  你对此有何高见
Castle, do you have a theory
介意说出来和大家分享一下么
that you would like to share with the class?
我...只是一个金发美女被勒死
Well, I-I--it's just that, pretty blonde girl, strangled,
尸体摆成睡觉的姿势
laid out like she was asleep.
都是四年前的事了
That was four years ago.
对  但他仍在逃  这是他的作案手法
Yes, but he was never caught. This is his M.O.
而且这女的绝对是他的菜
And she is certainly his type.
我写《屠杀来临》时调查过他
I researched him for "When it comes to slaughter."
是吗  那你该知道他只在
Yeah? Well, then you should know that
受害人的公寓行凶
he killed his victims inside their apartments,
而非横街窄巷
not in alleyways.
他还会将她们摆成
And he posed them
双手合拢放在胸前的殡葬姿势
in a funeral pose with their hands clasped in front of them.
也许他改变手法了
Maybe he's switching up his act.
或者极有可能只是一件单纯的
Or this just could be a crime of opportunity
年轻女士被杀案
where a young woman was murdered.
罗素女士  你女儿有跟你提过
Mrs. Russo, did your daughter ever talk to you
被跟踪吗
about being followed?
没有  也没有类似事件
No. Nothing like that.
你能想到有谁
Can you think of anyone that
会去伤害她吗
might have wanted to harm her?
有情感问题吗
Any relationship problems?
她连约会都没有
She wasn't even dating.
她大多数时间都在工作
Pretty much all she did was work.
-在电视公司工作对吗  -嗯
- At the, uh, cable company, right? - Mm-hmm.
她和同事之间有矛盾吗
Did she have any issues with anyone there?
呃...和办公室一个男职员
Uh... There was a man at her office.
-他叫什么名字  -她没说
- What was his name? - She didn't say.
但他老盯着她看  像个变态
But he stared at her a lot, like some pervert.
-来得真快  -鸡毛信对她可有效了
- That was quick. - 9-1-1 has that affect on her.
-你有何发现  -按你的吩咐
- What'd you find? - I pulled all the files
我翻出了他的所有旧档案
on all his past murders, just like you asked.
那可是我的想法
I-I believe that was my idea.
对  但我只听她的命令
Yeah, but I only listen when it comes from her.
随便啦  你继续说
Anyway, you were saying?
他会用四分一英寸的
He choked them using a 3-strand,
3股绞绳勒死受害人
twisted quarter-inch rope.
根据嵌入皮肤的纤维
Based on the fibers found embedded in the skin,
我们知道绳子是绿白相间的尼龙绳
we know that the rope is green and white nylon.
这点我可没印象
I don't remember that.
那些细节从来没公开过
Those details were never made public.
来看看这个
Now check this out.
勒痕完全一致
The marks are identical.
这次也发现了一摸一样的绿白相间纤维
I found the exact same green and white fibers.
是他干的
It is him.
三重杀手回来了
The triple killer is back.
四年前你们还寂寂无名时
For those of you living in a cave four years ago,
三重杀手  或称为3XK
the triple killer, or 3XK,
曾因一周内勒死三位女性而得此绰号
got his nickname by strangling three women in a week,
随后他销声匿迹一个月
dropping out of sight for a month,
然后再出来杀多三个后  便无影无踪了
and then killing three more, then he disappeared.
我曾是调查这六宗
I served on the task force that
谋杀案的特遣队一员
investigated those six murders.
联调局给出了识别
An FBI profile was as close as
嫌疑人的最贴近的侧写
we came to I.D.'ing a suspect.
联邦政府的人说他是一位白人男性
The feds say he's a white male,
-年龄在25至45岁之间  -说我呢
- 25 to 45 years old... - Could be me.
和母亲关系不和
with a dysfunctional relationship with his mother.
我也是哎
Still me.
他有一份乏味琐碎的工作
He has a menial, unimportant job.
就是你  没错了
Definitely you.
就冲你这句话  我下本书换埃斯波西托当主角
Just for that, I base my next book on Esposito.
他会摸透她们的习惯
He'd learn their habits,
然后假扮成
and then gain access to their apartments
保安或维修工
by disguising himself
进入受害人的公寓
as a security guard or a repairman,
接着勒死她们
and then he strangled 'em.
最后将她们的尸体
Then he posed their bodies
摆成躺在棺材的样子
as if they were lying in a coffin.
你说他干这些是为何呢
What do you think that's all about?
可能是在重演某种可怕的早期创伤
Probably reenacting some terrible early trauma.
最后二个要点
Two final points--
看来三重杀手四年后重出江湖了
the triple killer seems to be back after four years.
必定事出有因
There must be a reason.
也许他刚出狱或重回此地
Maybe he just got out of prison or returned to town.
他可能改变了作案手法
He may have altered his M.O.
但我们先假定他的作案规律没变
But let's assume that he's working under the same clock--
依然是一周三场谋杀
three murders, one week.
根据琳达·罗素的死亡时间
Based on Linda Russo's time of death,
今天已经是第三天了
we're already into day three.
大伙  快点行动起来
Let's move on this, people.
关于死者母亲提过的那个变态
Hey. That perv the mom told us about?
琳达的同事马上就想到是谁了
Linda's colleagues knew who he was right away.
保罗·麦卡德
Paul Mccardle.
他是死者办公室的园艺工
He works at her office as a horticultural technician.
什么工
A what?
也就是  专给植物浇浇水
Uh, you know, he's the guy who waters the plants,
给假树擦擦尘的人
dusts the fake ficus,
至少在昨天辞职前他还是干这些
or at least he was until he quit yesterday.
时间拿捏得真准啊
That's interesting timing.
他累积了两位数的家庭投诉
I see domestic complaints by the double digits.
投诉人是他妻子
Filed by his wife.
是前妻  他们结婚四年
Ex-wife. They were divorced last month
上个月离婚了
after being married for four years.
这么说来  在某种程度上他的确被释放了
So in a way, he did just get out of prison.
不仅如此
It gets even better.
琳达的邻居回忆说几天前
Linda's neighbors said they remember seeing
曾有辆红色的森特拉汽车停在她公寓楼下
a red Sentra parked outside her apartment a few days ago--
-跟麦卡德的一样  -带他过来
- The same vehicle Mccardle has.  - Let's get him in here.
-找我来有啥事  -关于琳达·罗素
- So what's this about?  - Linda Russo.
两天前  下午六点至午夜时分你在哪里
Where were you 2 nights ago between 6:00 and midnight?
我在星道球馆跟几个朋友打保龄球
Um, I was bowling with some buddies at, uh, galaxy lanes.
你为什么要
So why did you decide to
放弃园丁的工作
abandon your career as a horticultural technician?
我只是想过新的生活
I-I just wanted to move on.
是因为你借用那份工作来监视和跟踪琳达
Because you used that job to watch linda, to stalk her.
一旦她死了  就没理由逗留了吧
And once she was dead, why stick around?
不是的  我是无辜的
That is not true. I'm innocent here.
你看起来可不无辜
Well, you don't look innocent.
话说回来  你还真是个
No, as a matter of fact, you give new meaning
被"逼问得直冒冷汗"的嫌疑人啊
to the phrase "Sweating a suspect."
没错  我很爱流汗  不行么
Okay, yeah, I perspire a lot, okay?
我身体不好
I have a medical condition.
那都是小问题  你现在麻烦大着呢
Well, that's the least of your problems, Mr. Mccardle.
你跟踪琳达·罗素是众所周知的事
Your fixation with Linda Russo was well known,
而且你有对妇女施暴的案底
as was your history of violence against women.
有人看见你的车停在她公寓楼下
Your car was seen outside of her apartment,
现在她死了
and now she's dead.
我从没碰过她
I never touched her.
我对琳达很着迷  我对她很着迷
I had a thing for linda, okay. I had a thing for linda,
我的确把车停在她家楼下了
and I parked out in front of her place.
可三天来我从没
But I haven't been anywhere near there
靠近过那里  明白吗
in three days, okay?
-因为有人威胁过我  -什么人
- Not since that guy threatened me.  - What guy?
我被一个保安赶了出来
I-I got--I got rousted by some security guy,
他让我别再纠缠她了
and--and he told me to move on.
我真的被吓到了
And it really freaked me out,
从那之后我就没去过那里了
and I haven't been back there since.
真的  我发誓
I swear. That's the truth.
"瀑布汗先生"  他的不在场证明成立
So sweaty von sweats-a-lot? His alibi is holding.
星道球馆的经理证实他在那打保龄球
The manager of galaxy lanes has him throwing gutter balls
从五点直到打烊
5:00 until close.
那保安有什么线索
What about the security guard?
莱恩去查了下  结果发现
Ryan checked into that. Turns out that there's
琳达所处的街区只有一栋楼聘用了保安
only one building on Linda's block that uses guards.
根据保安公司的记录
According to the security company,
没有与麦卡德及其车辆
no incident report was ever filed
有关的事故报告
against Mccardle or his vehicle.
所以他在说谎
So Mccardle was lying.
不一定  话说以前
Maybe not. You know, in the past,
三重杀手曾伪装过保安
the triple killer posed as a security guard.
也许那人根本就不是保安
Maybe our guard wasn't a guard after all.
也许是杀手赶走了麦卡德
Maybe it was the triple killer moving
以便行凶
Mccardle off of his turf.
不管是谁  他都在按计划行事
Well, whoever he is, he's sticking to his schedule.
有第二个人遇害了
We have a second victim.
翻译：小池 苏小黛 大卫熊 小易 千花 小蛮腰
时间轴：零    后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
她叫金·福斯特  28岁  室内设计师
Her name's Kim Foster-- 28, an interior designer.
颈部有同样的勒痕  一切都跟上个案子一样
Same rope marks on her neck, same everything.
-死亡时间是多久  -根据肝温推测
- When did she die?  - Uh, based on liver temp,
大致是在昨晚  可能傍晚时分
I'd say sometime last night, probably early evening.
邻居看到有个瓦斯工人于7:45左右离开
Neighbors saw a gas repairman leave at 7:45.
大楼没有看门人
No doorman on the building,
所以三重杀手是在对讲机上呼叫了她
so triple killer calls kim foster on the intercom,
说他要去检查下瓦斯泄漏问题
says he wants to check a gas leak,
她就让他进来了
she buzzes him in.
我查查来电者身份
Let me check the incoming caller I.D.S. Ah.
我不明白  他干嘛要用跟过去一样的手段
I don't get it. Why did he return to the old M.O.?
-他怀旧呗  -可他杀琳达·罗素是在条小巷里
- Nostalgia.  - He killed Linda Russo in an alley.
她的公寓也没有看门人  为何不在公寓动手
She didn't have a doorman either. Why didn't he
就像杀死其他被害者一样
just kill her in her apartment like all the others?
也许她有特别之处
Well, maybe she was special somehow.
死者的最后一通电话是7:35从前门打来的
Vic's last incoming call was at 7:35 from the front door.
一定是她让他进来了  然后
She must have been let him in, and boom,
他制服了她
He just overpowered her.
也许没那么简单  看看那些抱枕
Maybe it wasn't that easy. Look at those throw pillows.
抱枕怎么了
What's wrong with 'em?
她是室内设计师
Well, Kim Foster's an interior designer.
可这些抱枕被摆放地
These pillows have been arranged
非常随意  非常不美观
with a barbarian-like gracelessness.
像是粗鲁的男人所为  所以她反抗过
Like a man would do it. So she put up a fight.
他们在沙发上搏斗过
They struggled right here on the couch.
然后他重新摆放了这些抱枕试图掩盖
And then he reset the pillows to cover it up.
他可没经过专业训练  所以摆放得很不整齐
He's out of practice, so he's not so neat.
-哦耶  -什么
- Hup!  - What?
找到个硬币
Found a penny.
在命案现场捡到钱  还算走运么
Under the circumstances, is this still lucky?
等等  我也找到点东西
Wait. I think I found something, too.
"文斯"  你觉得是凶手的吗
Vince. You think it belonged to the killer?
也可能落在这好几周了
Or maybe it's been here for weeks.
我交给鉴证小组查一下
I'm gonna have to get C.S.U. to process this area.
头儿  有位唐森先生想见您
Sir... A Mr. Townsend wants a word.
带他进来
Bring him in.
卡尔
Cal.
好久不见啊
Good to see you.
玛丽还好吗
How's Marie?
还行吧
Uh... She's okay.
我们分居了
We're split up now.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
那些记者
Reporters...
他们一直跑到我家来
They keep coming to my door
问我对那个杀了我女儿的人
and asking me how I feel about...
做何感想
The man who killed my daughter,
还说他可能又逍遥法外了
and he might be on the loose again,
萨拉死后  在调查过程中
after Sara died and all through the investigation,
你一直对我直言不讳
you were always straight with me,
我现在只想知道
and I just need to know, you know...
他们说的  是真的吗
I mean, what they're saying, is it true?
我是说  他又回来了吗
I mean... Is he back?
是的
Yes.
卡尔  我们有线索了  很有用的线索
Cal, we got leads. We got good leads.
我们会尽全力将他缉拿归案
And we--we're doing all we can to chase 'em down.
只要我们捉住它  一定首先通知你
If we make an arrest, you'll be the first to know.
我保证
I promise you.
萨拉还活着的话  下周就29岁了
Sara would've been 29 next week.
别让他毁掉另一个家庭
Don't let him do this to another family.
那个名牌  鉴证小组那边没线索
Hey. There's no news from C.S.U.
我也没指望能有什么发现
on the nametag, not that I was expecting any.
很令人起疑啊  他为什么
It makes you wonder why he didn't pull
不用假扮瓦斯工那套手法对付琳达·罗素
that whole gas leak routine on Linda Russo.
我知道为什么  答案在这里
I know why. The answer's in here.
-笔录  -四年前的
- A transcript?  - From four years ago.
我查看了当年提供三重杀手线索的热线记录
I took a look at calls made to the triple killer tip line,
这条引起了我的注意
and this one stood out for me.
时间是2006年5月21日
It's from may 21, 2006,
是第六起命案后的一周
which was a week after the sixth murder.
一个女人打来电话并留了言
A woman called and left a message,
但她没敢留下姓名
but she was too afraid to leave her name.
可她提到自己住在第10和第24街区之间
But she did mention that she lived at 24th and 10th.
跟琳达·罗素一样
Same corner as Linda Russo.
她当时跟一个有线电视修理工同乘电梯
She was riding an elevator with a cable repairman
他把她吓坏了
who so creeped her out
为了早点摆脱他
that she got off a floor early
她甚至提前一层下了电梯
just to get away from him.
可是  修有线电视的都很吓人啊
Yeah, but cable guy are creepy--
那是工作需要
that's a job requirement.
可他不是修有线电视的
Except he wasn't a cable guy.
她说他带的工具箱不对
She said he wasn't carrying the right tools.
琳达·罗素是在有线电台工作的
And working for a cable company,
她肯定知道这点
Linda Russo would know that.
所以我查看了
Which is why I took a look
琳达·罗素四年前的电话记录
at Linda Russo's phone records from four years ago.
那通热线电话就是她打的
She's the one who made the call to that tip line.
所以她跟其他被害者不同
So Linda Russo was special.
她提前下了电梯
When she got off a floor early,
他知道她有所警觉了
he knew that she made him,
所以他放弃计划逃之夭夭了
So he dropped out of sight.
这也解释了他为什么要在户外杀她
Which also explains why he attacked her outside.
他知道她不会
He knew there was no way she'd
让自己进她的家门
let him into her apartment.
当年琳达·罗素看到了他的脸
Linda Russo saw his face,
四年后他还是来杀了她
and he came back four years later.
真是种另类的残忍
That's a special kind of ruthlessness.
鉴证小组在名牌上找到了一个指纹
Yo. C.S.U. Just got a partial on that nametag.
发现吻合的了
We got a match.
我们要找的人叫马库斯·盖茨
The man we're looking for is Marcus Gates--
42岁  身高6英尺
42, 6-foot tall,
体重180磅  浅棕色头发
180 pounds, with light brown hair.
还有个蛇形纹身从左臂环绕而下
He also has a snake tattoo running down his left arm.
指纹与金·福斯特被害现场找到的指纹一致
A print match ties him to Kim Foster's murder.
有一份监狱的心理评估报告称盖茨是
Now a prison psych evaluation calls Gates "A brutal,
"野蛮的高智商反社会人士"
Highly intelligent sociopath."
他曾因过失杀人和杀人未遂入狱
He's done time for manslaughter and attempted murder.
他最近一次被定罪  是因为在酒吧
His last conviction was for breaking a bottle
用酒瓶砸了一个人的脑袋  差点把人砸死
Over a man's head in a bar, almost killing him,
他被判在新新监狱坐了四年牢
for which Gates served four years in sing sing.
上个月刚放出来
He just got out last month.
没有明确地址  没有家人
No known address, no family.
他四岁的时候母亲就去世了
His mother died when he was 4 years old,
那之后他先后在多个寄养家庭暂住
and he was placed in a series of foster homes since then,
所以说找到他不会很容易
so he will not be easy to find.
各位  四年前
Listen, four years ago,
由于我们没能阻止他
this guy took the lives of six women
这个家伙杀了六个女人
because we didn't stop him.
我们现在知道"三重杀手"是谁
We know who the triple killer is.
我们知道他在寻找第三个目标
We know he's out there targeting his third victim.
在他找到她之前
Let's get him
抓住他
before he gets her.
嘿  老爸
Hey, dad.
-回来了  -大案子吗  这么晚才回来
- Hey. - Must be quite a case if it's keeping you out this late.
无非就是  有人杀人  有人被杀
Oh, you know, someone died, someone else did it.
秘密仰慕者吗
Secret admirer?
是啊
As a matter of fact, it is.
知道是谁了吗
You figure out who it was yet?
我听取了你的意见  决定还是不知道为妙
I took your advice and decided it's better not knowing.
他又在我的柜子里留了纸条
And he left another note in my locker.
他说如果我喜欢那支玫瑰  我就明天
He said if I like the rose, I should show him
上学时戴上它  表明心意
by wearing it at school tomorrow.
很浪漫吧
Isn't that sweet?
你觉得...这是个好主意吗
Well... Is that a good idea?
你男朋友艾什利会怎么想
W-what would your boyfriend Ashley think?
我怎么感觉是你对此有意见
I get a feeling it's not Ashley who has the problem.
我只是认为在你不知道对方是谁的情况下
I'm just not sure it's smart to go wearing some flower
戴着花出现不是个好主意
when you don't know who it's from.
你们学校又不是诺克斯堡[美国政府黄金库]
Your--your school is not exactly Fort Knox, all right?
谁都有可能在你的柜子里留纸条
Anyone could've put that note in your locker.
你的秘密仰慕者有可能是...变态一个
Your secret admirer could be some... pervert
拿着高倍双筒望远镜在远处看着你
watching you from afar with high-powered binoculars.
我要去睡觉了
I'm going to bed now.
晚安
Good night.
窗户要锁好哦  听到没
Could you lock your windows for me, please?
-好的  -一定哦
- Yes. - Please.
我要确认窗户一定要锁好
I'm gonna check and make sure they're locked.
-都弄好了  在这堆文件里  -我没
- No, I had it all set up. It was in this pile. - I don't
我可没搞懂你的摆放方式
I don't understand your system.
是你弄乱的
You're messing up my system.
伙计们  有盖茨线索吗
Hey, guys. Any news on Gates?
我的摆放很有效率
My system is efficient.
但是很蠢
And dumb.
这个我都看过了  在你那堆文件里
I already went through this one. It's on your stack.
-那是我的一种摆放方式  -那太蠢了
- It's part of my system. - Your system is dumb.
没有线索吗
So... Nothing?
是啊  找到了他住在泽西的叔叔
No. We tracked down an uncle in Jersey,
但是他有20年没见过盖茨了
but he hasn't seen Gates in 20 years.
我在和新新监狱的人通话
So I'm on the phone with sing sing
追查他在监狱的伙伴
to chase down prison associates.
贝克特探长  你还在吗
Detective Beckett, you still there?
是的  我还在
Yes, I'm still here.
好的  他还在监狱吗
Okay. And is he still doing time?
因吸毒首次入狱  知道了  谢谢
First-time drug offender. Got it. Thanks.
杰端·泰森
"Jelly Tyson"?
是"杰瑞"  卡塞尔
It's "Jerry," Castle.
盖茨被释放之后
When Gates got released,
他把所有东西都给了一个狱友杰瑞·泰森
he gave all of us stuff to Jerry Tyson, a fellow inmate.
如果他们两个是朋友
So if the two of them were friends,
杰瑞有可能知道在哪里能找到盖茨
Jerry might be able to tell us where we can find Gates.
现在才是"杰瑞"
Now it's "Jerry."
我还有三个月就能离开这鬼地方
I got three months left in this hellhole.
我要做的就是好好表现
All I want to do is do my time,
出狱  去看我的女友
get out, and go see my girl,
但是如果盖茨知道我跟警察谈了话
and it's never gonna happen if Gates gets wind
以上的那些都会变成一场空
that I talked to cops.
他不会知道
He won't.
你怎么保证
You don't know that.
他在这里有耳目
He's got reach in here.
他会弄死我的
He'll have me taken out.
情况是这样  杰瑞  不管你说不说
Here's the deal, Jerry-- whether you talk to us or not,
我都会在这陪你等上一天
I am willing to sit here all day.
这样的话
So it's gonna look like...
别人还是会以为你给我们透露了消息
you were spilling your guts to us.
好吧  但是你们要保证两分钟后让我回牢房
All right. But I want to be back in my cell in two minutes.
可以  你们是朋友吗
Fair enough. Were the two of you friends?
也许吧  如果狱友算是朋友的话
I guess. Whatever that means in here.
我在厨房干活
I work in the kitchen.
我帮他偷水果  他用来酿酒
I snuck him fruit so he could make pruno.
作为回报  他同意保护你是吧
And in return, he agreed to protect you?
是  现在他出狱了  我一个人在这耗着
Yeah. Now he's gone, and I'm in here, going it alone.
每个骗子都憧憬着当他出狱后
Every con I've ever known dreams of what he'll do
会干些什么  去什么地方
and where he'll go once he gets out.
盖茨和你提起过吗
Gates ever talk to you about that?
我记得他提起过一些脱衣舞俱乐部
I remember him talking about some strip clubs, and, um,
还提过一个他经常去喝酒的地方
there's a place he liked to go drinking. Um...
在肉类加工区附近
in the meatpacking district.
酒吧叫什么名字
What was it called?
野猪之类的
H-hog something.
名字跟野猪有关
Something about hogs.
我刚刚侦查过了  他在酒吧喝啤酒
I just did some recon. He's at the bar nursing a beer.
-里面有几个人  -总共有5个
- How many in there? - Five total--
盖茨  酒保  女服务员和两名顾客
Gates, the bartender, a waitress, and two drunks.
他也许携带了武器  我们行动要迅速
He may be armed. We take him quick.
不要给他劫持人质的机会
Don't give him a chance to take any hostages.
是他
It's him!
把手举起来
Let me see your hands!
Let's see your hands right now!
快点把手举起来  纽约警局
Right now, let's see your hands! NYPD!
-手举起来  纽约警局  -手举起来
- Hands up! Nypd! - Hands in the air right now!
你听到他说的了  把手举起来
You heard the man! Put your hands in the air
最好给我跪在地上
and get on your knees while you're at it!
哇  老头子都上阵了
Wow. You brought out the old guy, huh?
这说明一件事
That can only mean one thing.
你们很想抓到我
You want me in a bad way, right?
-闭嘴  -别忘了宣布我的权利
- Shut up. - Hey, don't forget to read me my rights.
因为少了必要程序让我跑掉你们就亏大了
Be a shame to get turned loose on a technicality.
跟我们走
Let's go.
冷酷  捉摸不透
Cold, implacable...
"三重杀手"异常的平静
The triple killer remains at ease,
身陷敌营却面无惧色
calm in the lair of his enemy,
心率每分钟只有50次
with a resting heart rate of 50,
做好了和审讯者鏖战的准备
set to match wits with his interrogators.
我只是想...
I... just wanted to bring
给这样的一个时刻增添一点文采
a literary flair to the moment, you know.
酒保说出了盖茨的住处
The bartender told us where Gates lives.
他好几次烂醉如泥
He's had to put him in a cab
都是酒保给他叫的出租车
on more than one occasion.
莱恩拿到了搜查令
Ryan's got a warrant,
他去搜查他的住处了
and he's searching his place right now.
这个案子咱们不能指望
We can't count on circumstantial
证据送上门来
evidence to carry this case.
我们得让他招供
We need to get this guy to run his mouth.
唯一能指向他的确凿证据
The only hard evidence we have
就是金·福斯特这起谋杀
on him is Kim Foster's murder.
问出她被害时  他在哪
Pin him down on where he was when she died.
卡塞尔
Castle...
这次旁观
Not this time.
盖茨先生  我是贝克特探长
Mr. Gates, I'm Detective Beckett.
不是我喜欢的类型
Not my type.
但是呢
But...
我可以为你破一次例
I would make an exception.
你认识金·福斯特吗
Do you know Kim Foster?
应该不认识
Doesn't ring a bell.
你见过这个女人吗
Have you ever seen this woman before?
头发挺漂亮
She has nice hair.
你到底见没见过她
Have you or haven't you seen her?
纽约市啊
Uh, New York city
这么大个地方
is a big place.
我是说  我们可能在街上擦肩而过吧
I mean, I could've passed her on the street, I guess.
我说的是更为亲密的接触
I'm actually talking about a more intimate interaction.
你去过她的公寓吗
Have you ever been in her apartment?
我去过很过公寓
I've been to a lot of apartments.
这栋楼在35街和8街交口
This building is at 35th and 8th.
她住在301室
She lived in 301.
你去过这个公寓吗
Were you ever in that particular unit?
-没有  -那你能解释一下
- No. - Well, then perhaps you can explain to me
为什么我们在她尸体附近的
how we found this nametag
这个名牌上  找到了你的指纹
with your fingerprint on it lying next to her body.
我还真能解释这个疑问
As a matter of fact, I can.
我还真想听听他怎么解释
Can't wait to hear this.
-我在帝国道具行工作  -那又怎样
- I work at the Empire Prop House. - And?
那里出租拍电影电视用的道具
And they rent props for movies and tv shows.
我知道道具行什么意思
I know what a prop house is.
我的工作就是归整道具
So that's my job. I stock props.
有无数这样的名牌
There's tons of nametags just like this one,
我至少碰过其中的一大部分
and I bet I've touched a hundred of 'em.
-去查查  看看他说的是否属实  -这就去
- Run that down. See if he's for real. - On it.
我们没有你的工作记录
There's no record of you having this job.
他们都是私下发工资
They pay me under the table.
对了  你可以告我逃税
Oh. Maybe you can get me for tax evasion.
你所在的这个道具行
This prop house where you say you work,
那里有制服吗
do they have uniforms there?
-有啊  -煤气公司的制服也有吗
- Sure. - Like gas company uniforms?
你能想到的制服  他们都有
Any kind of uniform you can think of, they got it.
你有把制服带回家吗
And have you ever taken any of these uniforms home?
在你住所里有制服吗
Do you have any in your possession?
你们在搜查我的住处吗
Are you guys searching my place?
是的  那里有没有制服
Yes, so if there are any uniforms there,
你也许可以告诉我
you may as well tell me.
我想看看搜查令
Wow. I'm gonna want to see the search warrant.
为什么
What for?
这是我的合法权利
It's my legal right.
在你出示搜查令之前  我无可奉告
And I'm done talking till you show it to me.
所以你们最好采取积极措施
So you better get with affirmative action back there
拿出新的游戏计划
and come up with a new game plan.
他想看搜查令  借此窥探我们的战术
He wants the search warrant to get a peek at our cards.
这怎么就能让他窥探到呢
How is that giving him a peek?
搜查令列明凶手使用的绳索  制服
The warrant lists ropes, uniforms,
还有金·福斯特  琳达·罗素
and other personal effects belonging to Kim Foster,
和其他6名受害人的私人物品
Linda Russo, and the other six triple killer victims.
查看搜查令
By looking at the warrant,
他可以估计我们的调查进展
he can gauge where we are in our investigation.
这可不是给他一小瞥
That's not giving him a peek.
而是亮出我们的全部底牌
That's showing him our whole hand.
他会得知我们怀疑他就是连环凶手
He'll know we think he's the triple killer.
他已经知道了
He already knows.
帝国道具行证实盖茨在他们仓库工作
Empire Prop confirmed that Gates works in their warehouse
有权使用胸卡
and had access to those tags.
他在金·福斯特被杀当晚7:02打卡下班
He clocked out at 7:02 the night of Kim Foster's murder.
帝国道具行位于林肯广场  也就是说
Now Empire is in Lincoln Square, which means
他有足够的时间去到她公寓
that he had enough time to get to her apartment
在7:35按下门铃
and push the intercom button by 7:35.
给他出示搜查令
Show him the warrant.
他可能会请律师  尽量阻止他
Odds are he will lawyer up, but try to stop him.
她应该怎么做呢
How is she supposed to do that?
她阻止不了他
I don't think she can.
原来不仅是
Turns out you got a lot more
金·福斯特让你头痛
on your mind than just Kim Foster.
我还看到七个女人的名字
I see the names of seven other women here.
莱恩
Ryan.
告诉我你有线索了
Tell me you got something.
目前还没有
Not so far.
没有绳索  没有制服
No rope, no uniform,
没有能把他和受害人联系在一起的线索
nothing that ties him to any of the victims.
继续找
Keep looking.
这个胸卡
The thing is, this nametag
也许是让我受调查的原因
is the probable cause for bringing me in.
但我已经解释了指纹
But I've explained the fingerprint
现在  我相信你已经核查了我的故事
And by now, I'm sure you've checked out my story.
事实上  我们还在核实中
Actually, we're still verifying that.
我知道这程序
I know how this works.
你没有理由扣押我
You do not have probable cause to hold me.
是么  我们不能扣押他吗
Is that right? Can't we hold him?
除非是在拍电影
Only in the movies.
那他就可以走了吗
So he can just walk outta here?
除非她证明他说谎
Unless she catches him in a lie and
这样才能扣押他
gives her cause to keep him.
我现在想离开了
I want to leave now.
好吧
Okay. Fine.
你可以离开
You can do that.
你的律师到场离开的那一刻
The second that you lawyer up and leave,
你就成为我们的重点调查对象
you become the focus of a major investigation.
这给你生活带来的不便
It will disrupt your life
将超出你的想象
in ways you can't even imagine.
我已经是重点对象了
I'm already the focus.
是吗  你可以不是的
Yeah? Well, you don't have to be.
说实话  我们并没有任何
Look, the truth is, we don't have any evidence
把你和那些谋杀案联系在一起的证据
that connects you to those murders.
这都归结于金·福斯特
It all boils down to Kim Foster.
即使你的指纹是碰巧在这胸卡上
Even if your fingerprints got on this nametag by accident,
根据你的前科  你依然是我们的嫌疑犯
with your record, you still look like a suspect to us.
金·福斯特对你是个麻烦
So Kim Foster's a problem for you.
但你可以清除这个麻烦
But you can get that problem out of your way.
你说你从未到过她的公寓
You said you've never been to her apartment.
昨晚7:35你在哪里
Where were you at 7:35 last night?
这对我有什么好处
What's in that for me?
如果你的不在场证据核实
If your alibi checks out,
我们就排除你的嫌疑
then we move on.
我们会追查真正的凶手
We go after the real killer.
我7点下班  如平常一样回家
I left work at 7:00. I walked home like I always do.
我到家大概是7:30  我整晚都在家
I got home, maybe 7:30, and I stayed in all night.
真是那样的吗
And you're sure about that?
当然
Absolutely.
这是盖茨家前的交通摄像头拍到的
This is off of a traffic cam across from Gates' apartment.
就是这个  这个可以证明他说谎
Well, this is it. This will prove that he was lying.
7:35时  他在去金·福斯特公寓的路上
7:35, he was on his way to Kim Foster's apartment.
等等
wait. Whoa. Whoa.
回放  停  停在那里
Back--stop. Stop. Stop there.
是他  7:31
That's him. 7:31.
不  不可能
No, that can't be.
是他  瞧  一样的鬓角
It is. Look. Same sideburns.
还有蛇的纹身
And there's his snake tattoo.
接着他从后门溜出去  前往金家里
Well, then he slipped out the back and went to Kim's.
他是怎样在4分钟内
How would he get from 101st to midtown
从101大街来到市中心  还换了衣服
and change clothes in... four minutes?
我不知道  但他确实做到了
I don't know, but he did it.
可以放大录像吗
Can we enhance this video?
你可以随心所欲放大录像
You can enhance it all you want.
却不能改变事实  我们得放他走
Doesn't change the facts. We gotta cut him loose.
头  我只是
Sir, I just--
我也不希望是这样  探长
I don't like this any more than you, detective,
但他的不在场证据核实了
But he alibis out.
看来我们搞错了
Well, looks like we had it all wrong.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
连环杀手还逍遥法外
With this triple killer fella running around,
你们最好看住你们爱的人
you all better keep your loved ones close.
我希望你们可以抓住他
I sure hope you catch him.
派人监视他
Put a surveillance detail on him.
我不想那个狗娘养的离开我们的视线
I don't want that son of a bitch out of our sight.
你今早看起来格外可爱
Oh, don't you look adorable this morning?
我今天要见到我的神秘仰慕者
I meet my secret admirer today.
我可以想象这画面
Oh, I can just picture the scene.
你和你的神秘仰慕者相约咖啡屋
You and your secret admirer agree to meet in the cafeteria.
你的目光扫过一张张长满痘痘的脸
You scan the array of pimply faces.
哪张脸是他的呢
Which one is his?
你那神秘仰慕者点了一客双份土豆泥
Your secret admirer uses the prearranged signal
那是你们预先约好的接头暗号
of a double helping of mashed potatoes on his plate.
他  帅气
He's... handsome,
虽不性感  但人畜无害的小模样分外撩人
charming in an asexual, nonthreatening kind of way.
不错  但神秘远不及此
Nice try, but it'll be so much more mysterious.
听听这个
Listen to this.
如果你想见面  我5点会在草莓地
"If you want to meet, I'll be at strawberry fields at 5:00."
我希望你也在
"I hope you'll be there, too."
不不不  不要去
No. No, no, no. No, you're not going.
你之前可是一个劲鼓动我
Before you were practically forcing me
去查查他是谁
to find out who he is.
不是去公园里  更不是你孤身一人
Not in the park. Not by yourself.
我去过很多次了
But I've been there a million times-- well,
等等  等等
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你第一张纸条是
The first note you got--
一束淡黄色头发
"Rope of flaxen hair."
一束  淡黄色  淡黄色就是金发
"Rope"? "Flaxen"? Flaxen is blonde.
我是红头发  你反应过度了
I'm a redhead. You're totally overreacting.
我要去见我的神秘仰慕者  仅此而已
I'm meeting my secret admirer, and that's all there is to it.
理查德  亲爱的  她是对的
Richard, darling, she's right.
你是无理取闹
You are being utterly irrational.
就好像当年我演那个
It's like when I was doing,
叫啥来着  《灵欲春宵》
Uh, "Who's afraid of Virginia Woolf?"
我还以为我的替补想下毒害我
And I thought my understudy was trying to poison me.
没错  那日常血检还是我付的
Oh, yeah. The daily blood tests I paid for.
等等  她确实下毒害你了
Wait. She did poison you.
她给你的瑞士巧克力是泻药
The swiss chocolate she gave you was a laxative.
给我的表演增加了紧迫感
It added a certain urgency to my performance.
但问题是  你让我也疑神疑鬼了
But the point is, you indulged my paranoia.
因此  我5点要到公园里
So therefore, I am going to be in the park, 5:00,
在合适的远处确保
at a discreet distance to make sure
阿丽克西斯的神秘爱慕者不是斧头杀手
that Alexis' secret admirer is not an ax murderer.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
-告诉我你已经逮捕了盖茨  -还早着呢
- Tell me you've arrested Gates.  - Not even close.
我不知道怎么办  卡塞尔
I mean, I don't know how, Castle,
他杀了金·福斯特  他还会继续杀人
but he killed Kim Foster, and he's gonna do it again.
一点进展都没吗
There's been no developments?
通常你打给我都有线索
Usually you call me with news.
你打来是询问我的意见
You called to seek my counsel.
我可没这么说啊
I wouldn't say it exactly like that.
不不不
No, no, no.
你希望我有天马行空的理论
You were hoping I had some wild theory,
类似敏锐的洞察力
some sort of penetrating insight
可以让我们找到突破口
that would lead us to a breakthrough.
那你有吗
Well... Do you?
没有  一筹莫展
Nah! I got nothin'.
我只需要一丝证据
I just need some piece of evidence.
他跟谁说过  任何事都好
I mean, someone that he talked to, anything.
如果盖茨向杰瑞
What if Gates confided in Jerry
透露之前的谋杀案
about the previous murders?
杰瑞不会告诉我们
Yeah, well, Jerry's not gonna talk to us.
他今早在监狱里被痛打了一顿
He got beaten up in the prison yard this morning,
他觉得盖茨跟这事有关
and he thinks that Gates had something to do with it.
听起来盖茨害怕
Sounds like Gates is afraid of
杰瑞·泰森知道的一些事
what Jerry Tyson knows.
离我远点
Get the hell away from me.
听着  杰瑞  我们只需要再多一点
Listen, Jerry, we just need a little more information
马库斯·盖茨的资料
on Marcus Gates.
我不是告诉你们了吗
Don't you guys get it?
多谢你们我现在死定了
I'm a dead man thanks to you.
那如果我们让你出去呢
Not if we get you out.
检察官愿意让你提早出狱
The D.A. has agreed to get you an early release
而且有警方保护
and police protection.
盖茨知道我有女朋友
Gates knows about my girlfriend
唐娜·加拉格  他会找上她的
Donna Gallagher. He could get to her, too.
我们保证他不会的
Well, then we'll make sure he doesn't.
我们必须抓住凶手  杰瑞
We gotta move on this, Jerry.
最后机会了
Last chance.
好吧
Okay.
我会合作  我接受这笔交易
I'll do it. I'll take the deal.
我们要知道
We need to know
盖茨曾经说过他袭击女人的事吗
did Gates ever talk to you about attacking women?
有一次
There was this one time.
他告诉我有个女人  萨拉  住在苏活区
He told me about this chick, um, Sara--down in soho.
很可能是萨拉·唐森
that could be Sara Townsend.
他告诉我他怎样闯进她家
He told me about how he busted into her place
然后事情失去控制
and things got outta control,
最后肯定变得非常糟
but it must been pretty bad,
因为盖茨说
cause Gates said
他担心会被警察逮捕
he was worried that the cops were after him,
于是他砸了一家伙的头
so he busts a bottle over this guy's head
进了监狱
to get himself locked up.
这样  他就有段时间可以安枕无忧了
That way, he'd be under the radar for a while.
这是不错的开始
That's a good start.
我是警探莱恩
My name's detective Ryan.
我现在是你的新死党了
I'm your new best friend.
这间旅馆在我们的监控下
This motel's under surveillance.
为了你的自身安全  你不能离开或打电话
For your own safety, you cannot leave or use the phone.
现在  你和我要
Right now, you and I
回想一遍盖茨跟你说过的任何事
need to go over everything Gates ever said to you,
甚至是些很白目或者不重要的事
even if it seems stupid or unimportant.
杰瑞的话与事实相符
Jerry's story squares with the facts.
萨拉·唐森是盖茨的第六个受害者
Sara Townsend was Gates' sixth victim,
而且她住在苏活区
and she lived in soho.
那用瓶子砸人被逮捕呢
What about assault with a deadly bottle?
也证实了  是在萨拉遇害后的一周
That fits, too. It came a week after Sara's death.
看来盖茨是故意让自己进监狱的
Looks like Gates sent himself up the river on purpose.
仍然不足以逮捕他  对吧
It's still not enough to arrest him, is it?
不  但要是杰瑞继续提供情报
No, but if Jerry has more tidbits like that,
或许能帮我们找到证据
it may help us get there.
我们找不到唐娜·加拉格
Yo, we can't locate Donna Gallagher,
而且她也没有听电话
and she's not picking up her cell.
长官  盖茨在哪里
Sir, where is Gates now?
在他的公寓  监控器显示
At his apartment. Surveillance says
他并没有离开大厦
he hasn't left the building.
联络唐娜的朋友和家人
Contact Donna's friends and family.
找出她在哪里
Find out where she is.
-我告诉杰瑞会保证她的安全  -好的
- I told Jerry we'd keep her safe. - All right.
你不能就这样逮捕他吗
Can't you just arrest this guy?
我是说  你知道是他做的
I mean, you know he did these things.
他有不在场证明
He has an alibi.
我们没法将他与犯罪现场联系起来
We can't put him at the murder scene.
他有时候合伙犯案  你知道的吧
He used partners sometimes. You know that, right?
同伙
Partner?
我们从没调查过任何同伙
We never ran across anything about a partner.
噢  没错  他说
Oh, yeah. He said
有个同伙帮他逃脱的
a-a partner helps him get away with things.
我想起来了
Though I-I get the idea
他从不跟同一个人合作两次
he never used the same partner twice.
杰瑞说盖茨有同伙
Jerry said that Gates used a partner.
同伙  这就解释了他的不在场证明
A partner. That's why he has an alibi.
让你的手下逮捕盖茨
Tell your guys to arrest Gates.
我知道他怎么杀害金·福斯特了  好的
I know how he killed Kim Foster. Okay.
盖茨说他每晚都在
Gates said he walks home every night
同一时间回家的  是吧
at the same time, right?
所以这道路监控器记录了那天
So this traffic cam footage from the day be--
等等  他在这里
Wait. There he is.
他在这里  好的  右边是盖茨
There he is. Okay. That's Gates on the right
在金·福斯特遇害那晚的录像
the night of Kim Foster's murder.
左边的是较早时间盖茨的录像
On the left, Gates from a night earlier.
-这里有什么不同  -他太矮了
- What's wrong with this picture? - He's too short.
所以说  要不是盖茨缩水了
So either Gates shrank...
要不这就是他的同伙
Or this is his partner.
他穿着盖茨的衣服
He wore Gates' clothing.
盖茨能去道具屋拿假发
Gates would've had access to wigs and disguises
和伪装物品
from the prop house.
这就是为什么盖茨可以同时
That's how Gates can be at
-出现在两个地方  -等等
- two places at once. - Wait.
这是什么
What's that?
呃  这是反光
Uh, it's a reflection
这是  这是汗的反光  汗的反光
From... from s--from sweat! From sweat!
那是"瀑布汗先生"哎
That's sweaty von sweats-a-lot!
那是保罗·麦卡德
That's Paul Mccardle.
这就是为什么他要监视琳达·罗素
That's why he was watching Linda Russo.
他就是同伙  他跟盖茨一起作案
He's the partner. He was working with Gates.
我要全面通缉麦卡德
I'm gonna put an A.P.B. out on Mccardle.
你最好把马库斯·盖茨也加上去
You better add Marcus Gates to that list.
长官  警员进他家后
Sir? When officers busted in to his place,
只找到一条绳梯向下连接着
all they found was a rope ladder going down to the rooftop
隔壁大厦的顶楼  盖茨逃走了
of the building next door. Gates is gone.
已经派警员搜查了那片区域
Got uniforms searching the area.
-没有盖茨的消息  -可能他找上唐娜了
- No sign of Gates. - Maybe he's going after Donna.
这样他还可以要挟杰瑞
That way he could punish Jerry, too.
有任何线索她在哪里吗
We got any leads on her where abouts?
埃斯波西托正和她的朋友通话
Esposito's talking to her friends right now,
但仍然找不到她
but she's still in the wind.
还有保罗·麦卡德和他的车也不见了
So is Paul Mccardle. His car is gone, and he is, too.
他的前妻也不知道他在哪里
Ex-wife has no idea where he is either.
但我查出他和盖茨的关系了
But I did find out how he and Gates are connected.
他们曾经一起在收养家庭生活
They were in a foster home together.
那么他们俩可能一起潜逃
So Mccardle could be with Gates.
将盖茨和麦卡德的照片发布在
Get photos of Gates and Mccardle
-飞机  巴士还有火车站  -好的
- to airport, bus, and train stations. - Yeah.
唐娜的邻居刚刚告诉我
One of Donna's neighbors just told me
她暂住在她姐姐家帮忙看门
she's house-sitting at her cousin's.
你有她的地址吗
Do you have an address?
-是的  但盖茨也是  -有家伙
- Yeah, but so does Gates. - Some guy dressed as
打扮成邮递员说有唐娜的包裹
a messenger said he had a delivery for Donna.
马上过去那里
Get there now.
纽约警局
NYPD!
起来  从她身上起来
Get off! Get off her! Aah!
我看你这次还怎么狡辩
I'd like to see you talk your way out of this one.
我会试着不让你失望
I'll try not to disappoint you.
我们在你口袋里找到了与三重杀手
We found the same kind of rope in your pocket
作案时一模一样的绳子
As was used by the triple killer.
我记得  男人是允许携带绳子的
Last I checked, a man's allowed to carry rope.
我觉得你希望被捕的  马库斯
I think you wanted to get caught, Marcus.
你在外面的世界什么也没有
There's nothing left for you out here,
但在监狱里  人们怕你
But in prison, people fear you.
你是老大
You're a shot caller.
而你希望能再次呼风唤雨
And you wanted to be king again.
你剩下要做的事
All's that left for you to do
就是再次犯案让我们查出
is to clear the air of all these murders
你就是凶手
and be done with it all.
想得美
Nice try.
这家伙永远不会乖乖就范的
This guy is never gonna give it up.
长官  我需要他的把柄  但我什么都没有
Sir, I need leverage and I don't have any.
没有任何目击者
There's no witnesses.
没有证据能将他与任何凶杀案联系起来
There's no proof that connects him to any of the murders.
唯一能起诉他的就是控告他袭击
The only thing that I've got him on is an assault charge.
嘿  麦卡德的全国通缉有消息了
Hey, we just got a hit on Mccardle's A.P.B.
他在圣本杰明医院
He's at st. Benjamin's hospital.
或许盖茨已经找上他了
Maybe Gates got to him.
长官  要是我能让麦卡德供出他
Sir, if I can get Mccardle to roll.
快去
go!
是的  呃  嘿  嗯
Yeah. Uh, hey, um--
好吧  卡塞尔  去吧  但不要妨碍他
Okay, fine, Castle, go. Just stay out of his way.
还有  莱恩
And, Ryan...
给我些能让他开口的东西
Get me something I can break him with.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我是警探莱恩  我想跟麦卡德先生说句话
I'm detective ryan. We'd like a word with mr. Mccardle.
你不能  他刚刚做完心脏手术
You can't have one. He just got out of heart surgery.
什么病
What for?
先天性瓣膜缺损
A congenital valve defect.
这病有可能导致出汗过度吗
Would that cause excessive sweating, by any chance?
是的  还有其他更严重的症状
Well, among other, more serious symptoms.
他急需做这个手术已经超过一年
He's been in dire need of surgery for over a year.
为什么现在才做
So why get it now?
他终于筹到钱了
Well, he finally came up with the money.
这手术费用高昂
It's kind of a costly procedure.
-有多贵  -大概十万美金
- How costly? - About $100,000.
呃  是谁付帐的
Uh... Who footed the bill?
那是保密消息
That's confidential information.
我们问过她前妻
You spoke to his ex-wife
她甚至不知道他在这里
she didn't even know he was here.
她痛恨这家伙  那么这花是谁送的
She hated the guy. So who sent the flowers?
麦卡德的手术跟盖茨一点关系也没有
Mccardle's surgery had nothing to do with Gates.
事实上  盖茨给他送了康复鲜花
In fact, Gates sent him get-well flowers.
这代表他关心他的收养兄弟
Which means he cares about his foster brother.
这就是你要的把柄
That's your leverage.
你需要我们等麦卡德录口供吗
You still need us to wait and talk to Mccardle?
不  告诉杰瑞他女朋友没事
No. Tell Jerry his girlfriend's fine,
而且他不用再因为盖茨担惊受怕了
and he doesn't have to worry about Gates anymore.
你不断回来索要更多的东西
You keep coming back for more.
这种女人正合我意
I look for that in a woman.
我们找到保罗了  他在圣本杰明医院
We found Paul. He's at st. Benjamin's.
我们知道他在金·福斯特遇害的那晚
We know that he pretended to be you
装扮成你的样子了
the night of Kim Foster's murder,
我会让他作供指证你的
and I'm gonna get him to testify against you.
你不了解保罗
You don't know Paul.
那么我们就另寻他法
Well, then we'll go another way.
我会以谋杀罪从犯的名义起诉他
I'll charge him with accessory to murder.
你不能这么做的
You can't do that.
我们当然可以
Actually, we can.
新新监狱对你来说可能是游乐场
Sing Sing might have been a picnic for you,
但是你觉得保罗在里面能撑多久
but how long do you think Paul is gonna survive in there?
保罗对谋杀根本一无所知
Paul didn't know what was going on.
他只是按我的去做而已
He only did what I told him.
想要证明这一点
The only way to prove that
你就要把完整的故事讲给我听
is by telling me the whole story.
你要保证保罗无罪
Only if Paul gets immunity.
白纸黑字写下来
And I want that in writing.
就是他吗
Is that him?
就是他
That's him.
盖茨先生  你承认杀害金·福斯特吗
Mr. Gates, did you kill Kim Foster?
是的  她们都是我杀的
Yes. I killed all of them.
说出她们的名字
I want their names.
琳达·罗素
Linda Russo,
在那之前还有萨拉·唐森
before that, it was Sara Townsend,
和其他五个女人
and five other women.
盖茨全招了
Gates confessed to everything.
得给我们这帮好人加上一分
We get to chalk one up for the good guys.
-干吗拉着个脸  -这要是我的书的话
- Why the long face?  - Because if this were a book,
我还是搞不明白那个手术的事
I still wouldn't understand the operation.
心脏瓣膜替换术
Valve replacement.
没什么大不了的  我爸也做过
It's no big deal. My dad had one.
我知道  可问题是他要是没钱的话
Yeah, it is if you don't have the money.
手术费是哪来的呢
Who paid for it?
我猜是盖茨给的
I'm guessing Gates did.
也许他入狱前藏了一笔钱
Maybe he stashed away some money from before prison.
有可能  但是他都出狱一个月了
Yeah, but he was out of prison for a month.
为什么等到现在才给麦卡德做手术呢
Why wait till now to do Mccardle's operation?
他需要麦卡德帮他完成琳达·罗素
Well, he needed Mccardle to help him with Linda Russo
-和金·福斯特的谋杀  -可能吧
- and Kim Foster.  - Yeah, I guess.
打包呢
Packing up?
只是整理一下我的东西
Oh, just getting my stuff together.
这些都是监狱里拿出来的
All that stuff from prison?
住的久了东西自然就多了
Well, you accumulate a lot of stuff,
在监狱里也不例外
you know, even in the slammer.
你对盖茨的推测是正确的
You were right about Gates.
他的确去找唐娜了
He did try to go after Donna.
-但是她现在没事了  -那盖茨呢
- But she's okay.  - And Gates?
他招供了  这件事结束了
He confessed. It's all over.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
你都不问问到底发生了什么吗
Aren't you gonna ask what happened?
你都没问过你女朋友唐娜怎么样
To your girlfriend Donna -- you didn't ask about her.
你只是问了盖茨而已  这不合理呀
You just asked about Gates. Doesn't make any sense,
除非
unless...
你早就计划好了她的死
She was supposed to die.
我不知道你在说什么
I-I don't know what y --
直到你出狱了
And Mccardle didn't get the money for the surgery
麦卡德才有钱做手术
until after you got out of prison.
他还要毁灭所有曾经入狱的证据
He's removing all evidence he was even there.
是他  他才是三重杀手
It was him all along. He's the real triple killer.
所控属实
Guilty as charged.
-干得好  探长  -谢谢  头
- Excellent work, detective.  - Thank you, sir.
希望你对卡塞尔也说一样的话
I hope you say the same to Castle.
倒是他人跑哪去了
Where is he, by the way?
我还以为他们早就该回来了呢
I thought that they would be back by now.
也许他跟莱恩去喝上一杯了
Maybe he and Ryan went out for a cold one.
这么一天下来  我也要喝上一杯
After a day like today, that's what I'm doing.
-想一起去吗  -当然  愿意奉陪
- You care to join me?  - Yeah. Yeah, I'd love to.
那咱们走吧
Then let's hit it.
盖茨故意入狱逃避追捕的故事
That story about Gates getting arrested,
实际上是发生在你身上的  对吧
that was your story, wasn't it?
你害怕谋杀案会暴露
You were afraid you were gonna get caught,
于是就躲进了监狱
so you hid in prison.
可惜你没早点发现
Too bad you didn't figure that out sooner.
可惜你没早点跑掉
Too bad you didn't leave sooner.
警察随时都会到
The cops will be here any minute.
看来莱恩探员在过来之前
Looks like detective Ryan called the precinct
已经打过电话给分局了
just before he got here.
短时间内不会有人找我的
There won't be anybody missing me for a while,
等他们想起我来  我早就消失了
and by the time they do, I'll be long gone.
你跑不了多远的
You won't get far.
他们已经知道你的名字  你的长相
They already have your name, know your face.
这些都可以改的  以前也干过
I'll change those. Done that before.
这也正是其中乐趣之一
That's part of the fun of it.
像陷害盖茨一样好玩吗
Fun like setting up Gates?
保罗·麦卡德是他在这个世界上
Paul Mccardle was the only person in the world
唯一在乎的一个人
that he cared about.
知道这点以后  剩下的就简单了
Once I learned that, the rest was easy.
说不准什么时候会用得上警徽呢
You never know when you'll need one of these.
再说盖茨喜欢监狱
Besides, Gates liked prison.
你把盖茨该知道的都告诉了他
You taught Gates everything he needed to know
好让他帮你顶罪
to take the fall for the triple killer murders.
之后你只需要支付保罗的手术费
After that, all you had to do was pay for Paul's surgery,
就可以溜之大吉了
and you could walk away scot-free.
计划不错  就被这个大帆布袋给毁了
That's a beautiful plan...undone by a duffel bag.
计划没毁  我还好端端地站在这呢
I'm not undone. I'm right here.
我会换个地方重新开始
I'll relocate. I'll start over.
看我从你眼前溜掉
It must eat you alive,
你却无能为力  一定很抓狂吧
knowing that you came so close to catching me.
但可惜  胜者为王  败者为寇
But this is a winner-take-all type of game.
杰瑞
Oh, Jerry.
用枪吗
Shooting?
这不是你的风格
It's not your style.
你还真是一点都不了解我呀
Oh, you really don't know me at all, do you?
你并不难琢磨
Oh, it's not complicated.
你是被单亲母亲带大的
You were raised by a single mother.
她一头金发  很是漂亮
She was blonde. Oh, she was beautiful.
但是  她根本就不想要你
But...she never wanted you.
我猜当你在
When you were, what,
大概十二岁左右  她突然暴毙
12 I'm guessing, she died suddenly.
大概是嗑药过量
Let's say drug overdose.
你被送去寄养  可惜不是什么好人家
You go into foster care, the bad kind.
你如此地憎恨
You have so much hate...
憎恨你的母亲
So much hate towards your mother
因为她遗弃了你
for abandoning you...
所以你杀这些女人是为了报复她
that you kill these women to get back at her.
但是你把她们摆出一副安详的样子
But you leave them looking peaceful,
因为纵使你对你母亲有无比憎恨
because as much as you hated your mother...
你内心深处仍然爱她
You loved your mother.
我猜的差不多吧
Am I getting warm?
你被死亡所吸引
You're drawn to death.
你喜欢接近死亡  因为这让你兴奋
You like to be around it 'cause it thrills you.
而这又是为什么呢
Now where does that come from?
你内心深处被压抑的冲动吗
Your own suppressed impulses?
你到底想
How close...
离死亡
To death...
有多近呢
Do you want to get?
别乱说话
Don't say anything you shouldn't.
喂
Hello.
亲爱的  我只是想告诉你
Darling, I just wanted you to know,
你的阴谋论毫无根据
your conspiracy theories are completely unfounded.
我的阴谋论
My conspiracy theories?
阿丽克西斯的秘密仰慕者
Alexis' secret admirer
是艾什利  她男朋友
is Ashley, her boyfriend.
太好了  谢谢
Oh, that's great. Thanks.
他是个魅力四射的小伙子
Yeah, and he's a very charming young man.
总之不用担心  结局皆大欢喜
So anyway, no need to worry. All's well that ends well.
理查德
Richard?
我爱你
I love you.
该说的都说完了
I don't think there's anything more to say.
-卡塞尔  -安全  他跑了
- Castle?!  - Clear. He's gone.
我没事  给莱恩叫辆救护车
I'm fine. Ryan needs an ambulance.
-用不着救护车  -到底发生什么事了
- No, I don't.  - Hey, what the hell happened here?
你没事我太高兴了
I'm so glad that you're okay.
他才是三重杀手  他安排盖茨冒名顶替
He's the triple killer. He set Gates up to be a copycat.
我知道  当你跟莱恩来找杰瑞
I know. I did the math when you and Ryan
却一直没回去  我就在琢磨这件事了
didn't come back from talking to Jerry.
你怎么知道要到这来找我们
How did you know to come here?
你妈打了个电话给我
Your mom called.
她说你跟她说你爱她
She said that you told her that you loved her,
她就知道肯定大事不妙了
and she figured something must be terribly wrong.
我就知道她会明白的
I figured she might.
干得好
Good girl.
给
Here you go.
谢谢
Thanks.
跟我说说  卡塞尔
Tell me something, Castle.
他为什么留你活口
Why did he let you live?
为了惩罚我
To punish me.
让我为毁了他的计划而付出代价
To make me pay for ruining his plan.
现在他又要开始杀戮了
Now he's gonna kill again,
就因为我没能阻止他
all because I couldn't stop him.
而我觉得如此
And I feel so...
我了解你的感受
I know the feeling.
我知道你了解
I know you do.